Name : Leo van den Heuvel

Address : Lariksdreef 37

3137 PH Vlaardingen

The Netherlands

Phone : (+31) (0)6 52489044 Email : L.vdheuvel@xs4all.nl

Date of Birth : 13 July 1957

Marital Status : Partnership since 1989, one son (age 6)

Manager on an operational and business-support level with experience in process management. Member of the MT.

Experience with service management, production management, project management and sales management.

Successful in creating and (re-)positioning departments and organisations, both national and international as well as in improving and streamlining processes.

Analytical and problem solving attitude. Systematic, thematic approach.

Customer focused and "service" oriented.

Result driven with a no-nonsense, get-the-job-done attitude. Team player. Open, honest and reliable.

Professional Experience:

(2010 – present) | Istec International b.v.:

Industrial process instrumentation, vibration measurement

systems and service.

3/2010 – present Account Manager

Managing the sales department, setting and achieving goals and targets

Reporting to the general director of the company

Acquisition of new customers

Responsible for the instrumentation, sales and service in the Europoort,
 Zeeland & Antwerp area

Zeelanu & Antwerp area

Control of on-site projects

Responsible for the integration of sales and service groups

Responsible for implementation of ISO9001:2008 (documentation,

processes, internal- & external audits, etc)

(10/2009 – 3/2010) Unemployed:

Searching for a new, inspiring and challenging role.

(continued... Professional Experience ...)

(1991 - 1/10/2009)

Emerson Process Management:

Assembly and Test of customer specific control systems used in processing industries like refineries, (petro-) chemical, pharmaceutical, etc.

2007 - 1/10/2009

Manager Systems Assembly Support

Responsible for the consolidation and expansion of the European Systems Assembly site in Slovakia

- Responsible for setting the local business goals and directives and cascading this into the local organisation
- Responsible for the operational and financial performance of the Business Unit (Euro 35M+)
- Train the Engineers, implement Solutions Engineering
- Responsible for setting up an European Engineering Solutions Centre
- Control of workmanship standards
- Implementing a lean assembly line (result: 40% reduction in throughput time)
- Implementing process automation in the engineering group (result: 60% reduction in throughput time)
- Design and implement European-wide production standardisation
- Implement new product lines to be centrally assembled in Europe (PWS-Ovation)
- Responsible for resolving the technical-, logistic- and compliance issues
- Responsible for the transfer of Site Engineering knowledge and activities from the European countries into the European Systems Assembly Site in Slovakia
- Set up the relationship with the sales offices in all European countries
- Driving these sales offices to change longstanding, deeply ingrained practices

2006 - 2007

Project Manager for moving the activity of Systems Assembly from Rijswijk, NL to a low cost country (Slovakia).

- Create the appropriation request and follow up for approval
- Manage the selection of the best location in Eastern Europe and/or Asia
- Manage the renovation and equipment of the new building
- Creating profiles and job descriptions for all functions in Slovakia
- Selecting and hiring of personnel in Slovakia (65 staff)
- Training and coaching the local plant manager in Slovakia
- Responsible for the training of new personnel and transfer of knowledge
- Responsible for closing down the facility in Rijswijk, NL, including all redundancies
- Manage the transfer of equipment, inventory and order book
- Manage the start up of the Slovakian facility
- Responsible for setting the local business goals and directives and cascading this into the local organisation
- Implementing Systematic Management, QFD, process control and KPI's

(continued... Professional Experience ...)

2001 – 2007	 Manager Worldwide Systems Assembly Daily operational management of the Systems Assembly business unit, 22 permanent employees, max 16 temporary employees Financial responsibility, Euro 20M+ per annum Responsible for delivery of customer specific solutions in Europe (DeltaV) and Worldwide (RS3 & Provox) Driving the change from Production Engineering to Engineering Solutions Implementation of process improvements, lean manufacturing and standardisation Driving continuous improvement projects Control of workmanship standards Co-operating with other departments in the Worldwide Supply Chain in Europe, Singapore, India and USA Implementation and control of Systematic Management, QFD, process control and KPI's Results: 94% on time delivery, throughput time reduced from 14 weeks to 6 weeks, ITO improved from 4.5 to 12.5
1998 – 2001	 Manager Planning & Inventory Control and Product Support Inventory control, ITO & forecasting Capacity planning for the shop floor Provide technical support and training to all people in the business unit Maintaining workmanship standards and controlling process improvements Database maintenance for JDE
1993 – 1998	 Manager Product Support Creating and leading a support department Provide technical support and training to all people in the business unit Implement and maintain workmanship standards Implement process improvements Quality control and implementation of ISO9000 Define, create and execute database maintenance for JDE
1993	Project leader for moving Provox assembly activities from England to Holland
1991 – 1993	Manager Repair Centre
(1984 – 1991)	Granada Computer Services: Independent provider of service and repair for mainframe computers and peripheral equipment (previous DPCE Ltd).
1986 – 1991 1984 – 1986	Manager Repair Centre Service Engineer
(1982 – 1984)	Hewlett Packard: Sales and service of PCs, mainframe computers and peripheral equipment. Service Engineer

(continued... Professional Experience ...)

(1979 – 1980) Apprenticeships:

Hollandse Signaalapparaten bv, Hengelo

KPN International Branch Exchange, Rotterdam

Verolme Elektra bv, Maassluis

Education:

1969 - 1976 High School (Atheneum-B)

1976 - 1981 Technical College – Bachelor degree (HTS-Electronics)

1986 - 1987 Middle Management

Additional and internal training courses, amongst which:

- Situational Leadership (Granada, 1990)
- Communicative Manager (Emerson, 2005)
- Think Customer Facilitator (Emerson, 2006)
- Leadership Training by Mark McGregor (Emerson, 2006 & 2007))
- Systematic Management & QFD (Tesseract & Emerson, 1997 present)
- Export Compliance (Emerson, 2001 present)
- JCIT Lean Manufacturing Principles (2002)
- Various technical training courses (Emerson, 1991 present)
- Vibration measurement systems (Istec, 2010)
- Non-contact measurement of distances & temperature (Istec 2010)

Language Skills:

Fluent in Dutch and English Average in German